Finding aid for the Xavier University Academic Technology Committee records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Academic Technology Committee records
1965-2010
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Academic Technology Committee
1 linear feet (2 boxes)
This collection includes meeting minutes and related papers of the Academic Technology Committee and its predecessor committees.
XUA-25
History of Xavier University Academic Technology Committee
From about 1965 to 1988 there was a committee simply called the Computer Committee. During the summer of 1988, this committee was disbanded and replaced by the Academic Computing Committee. Sometime between 1993 and 1997 its name was changed to the Academic Computing and Information Technology Committee (ACITC). In November, 2000, the name was changed again to the Academic Technology Committee (ATC). In August, 2013, the Academic Technology Committee (along with the University Technology Committee) were both eliminated and replaced by just one committee called the Xavier Technology Committee (XTC).
The charge of this Committee, as stated in "Committee Descriptions, 2010-11" was the following: "On matters involving technology for instruction and academic research, the Academic Technology Committee: 1. Advises the Academic Vice President/Provost and the Vice President for Information Resources; 2. Receives proposals from the faculty and the college deans; 3. Studies, recommends and prioritizes initiatives, and 4. Serves as a clearinghouse for information." (See Committee Descriptions, 2010-11)
Scope and Content
This collection includes the minutes and related papers of the Academic Technology Committee and predecessor committees for the years 1965 to 2010. The collection is not complete, as minutes are missing for a number of years.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically.
Separated Material
Committee minutes from 2005 to 2012 are also found electronically on the Xavier University Archives permanent storage drive.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Data Processing; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Planning; Educational technology
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Computer Committee Papers, 1965; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Computer Committee Minutes and Related Documents, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Computer Committee Minutes and Related Documents, 1973; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Computer Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Academic Computing Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Academic Computing Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Academic Computing Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Academic Computing and Information Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Academic Computing and Information Technology Committee Documents, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Academic Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Academic Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 1998-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Academic Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Academic Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Academic Technology Committee Minutes and Related Papers, 2005-2010 (Box 2, Folder 14)